-还是没有回应吗  -没有
- Still nothing? - Nothing.
食物法庭  你确定他们说食物法庭
Food court? You sure they said food court?
抱歉  是不是我的翻译水平让你失望了
I'm sorry, have my translation skills been letting you down?
我们不清楚是不是你的孩子
We don't know it's your kids.
不  我们清楚
Yes, we do.
-那是什么  -有东西在里面
- What is that? - There's something in there.
-不  -老天爷
- No! - Jesus Christ.
跟她说话  让她保持清醒  好吗
Keep her talking. Keep her awake, okay?
老天爷
Jesus Christ.
坚持住  坚持住
Stay awake, stay awake.
把她挪到这边  这边
Let's get her on this side, on this side.
-放松  放松  -这...
- Easy, easy, easy, easy. - It's, uh...
其实还没那么糟  有个...
You know, it's not actually that bad. There was a...
我足球队的守门员  贝丝·威尔德菲尔
The goalie on my soccer team, Beth Wildfire,
另外一个球员撞到了她的腿上
this other girl slid into her leg,
骨头都从膝盖支出来了
and the bone came out of her knee,
-大概有六英寸长  太可怕了  -罗宾
- six inches or something, it was insane. - Robin.
-什么  -你是在帮倒忙
- Yeah? - You're not helping.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
还好吗  一一
Okay. All right, El?
这会非常疼的
This is gonna hurt like hell, okay?
-好的  -我要你保持完全不动
- Okay. - Need you to stay real still.
拿着  咬着这个  好吗
Here, you're gonna want to bite down on this, okay?
老天爷
Jesus Christ.
我的天
Holy shit. Holy shit.
来吧
Do it.
好
Okay.
该死
Oh, shit.
-乔纳森  -别说话
- Jonathan! - Stop talking!
-该死  -不  住手
- Goddamn it! - No! Stop it!
停  停
Stop! Stop!
我自己来
I can do it.
天呐
God!
怪奇物语  第三季
第八集  星庭之战
星庭商场
吸灵魔  它在霍金斯造了这个怪物
The Mind Flayer, it built this monster in Hawkins,
来阻止一一
to stop El,
杀了她便能入侵我们的世界
to kill her and pave a way into our world.
它差点就得手了  这只是它的一小部分
And it almost did. That was just one tiny piece of it.
这个怪物有多大
How big is this thing?
很大
It's big.
-至少两米高  -是的
- Thirty feet, at least. - Yeah.
它摧毁了你的小屋
It sorta destroyed your cabin.
抱歉
Sorry.
我确认一下  这头
Okay, so, just to be clear, this...
这头弄伤一一的大肉球蜘蛛
this big fleshy spider thing that hurt El,
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
是某种巨型武器吗
it's some kind of gigantic... weapon?
-是的  -但并不是用螺钉和金属打造的
- Yes. - But instead of, like, screws and metal,
翻译     草草   屯栗子
吸灵魔是用融化的人体
the Mind Flayer made its weapon...
打造它的武器
with melted people.
翻译     VI君   二糯米
-没错  -好吧
- Yes, exactly. - Yeah, okay.
我只是想再确认一下
I... Yeah, I'm just making sure.
这头怪物真的还在外面  还活着吗
Are we sure this thing is still out there, still alive?
翻译     酥ki酱
一一暴揍了它一顿  但它的确还活着
El beat the shit out of it, but, yeah, it's still alive.
校对     小酸奶
但如果我们再将入口关闭
But if we close the gate again...
我们就能将大脑控制切断
We cut the brain off from the body.
就能杀了它
And kill it.
理论上是这样
Theoretically.
时间轴     西查
后期     8T
这就是阿列克西所谓的"枢纽"
Okay, this is what Alexei called "the hub."
这个枢纽是能通向保险库的
Now, the hub takes us to the vault room.
总监     小酸奶
入口在哪
Okay, where's the gate?
就在这  我不知道图上的比例是多少
Right here. I don't know the scale on this,
但我觉得应该离保险库非常近
but I think it's fairly close to the vault room,
大概有个50英尺
maybe 50 feet or so.
500英尺还差不多
More like 500.
怎么  你还想在里面跳上一段华尔兹吗
What, you're just gonna waltz in there
你以为那是共产主义迪斯尼乐园吗
like it's commie Disneyland or something?
抱歉  你是谁
I'm sorry, who are you?
艾瑞卡·辛克莱  你又是谁
Erica Sinclair. Who are you?
莫里
Murray...
鲍曼
Bauman.
听好了  鲍曼先生
Listen, Mr. Bunman,
我不是想对你指手画脚
I'm not trying to tell you how to do things,
但我曾在那鬼地方待过一天
but I've been down in that shithole for 24 hours.
恕我直言  如果你们照他说的做
And with all due respect, you do what this man tells you,
你们都会死
you're all gonna die.
抱歉
I'm sorry,
这个四岁的小屁孩有什么资格跟我说话
why is this four-year-old speaking to me?
我十岁了  你个秃头混蛋
Um, I'm ten, you bald bastard!
-艾瑞卡  -这就是事实
- Erica! - Just the facts!
他说得对  你们都会死的
She's right. You're all gonna die,
但这可以避免
but you don't have to.
-抱歉  我能看看吗  -请
- Excuse me. Sorry, may I? - Please.
看到这个房间了吗  这是贮藏库
Okay, see this room here? This is a storage facility.
这有个小舱口
There's a hatch in here
能进入他们的地下通风系统
that feeds into their underground ventilation system.
这能通向他们的武器库
That will lead you to the base of the weapon.
这下面就像迷宫一样
It's a bit of a maze down there,
但有我和艾瑞卡  我们能给你们带路
but between me and Erica, we can show you the way.
你们能给我们带路
You can show us the way?
别担心  你们尽管去当英雄
Don't worry, you can do all the fighting
和那些危险的东西作战
and the dangerous hero shit,
我们只是你们的
and we'll just be your...
导航员
navigators.
不行
No.
Nope.
那就这样了
Well, that settles it.
他死定了  他们都死定了
He's gonna die. They're gonna die.
是的  非常有可能
Yep, most likely.
你们就逃出来了
You guys survived.
差点不辞那个了
Barely.
我们在下面很需要你们
We could've really used you guys down there.
我们这里也很需要你
Could've used you up here, too.
是啊  我们很想你  伙计
Yeah, man. We missed you, dude.
是啊  非常想你
Yeah. Big-time.
我也很想你们的
I missed you guys, too.
非常想念
Big-time.
可别哭了  书呆
Please don't cry, nerds.
-艾瑞卡  -你再叫我名字一遍试试
- Erica. - Keep saying my name, see what happens.
接着  你可以导航  但必须是在安全的地方
Hey, heads up. You can navigate, just from someplace safe.
这没那么简单
It's not that simple.
-信号没那么强  -这个不行
- The signal won't reach. - Not with this.
你得找一个高频率带的设备
You need something with a high enough frequency band
用苏联人的的无线电塔转接
to relay with the Russians' radio tower.
但那你得找一个
But for that to work, you need someone
既见过他们通讯室
who has both seen their comms room
还有超强无线塔操作能力的家伙
and has access to a super-powered handcrafted radio tower,
这人最好还去过霍金斯的最高点
one preferably already situated at the highest point in Hawkins.
等等
Oh, wait.
这不就是我吗
That's me.
你想让我们来导航  没问题
If you want us to navigate, you got us.
但我们需要抢在前面
But we need a head start.
还要一辆车
And a car.
天呐  这
Oh, man, now this...
这才对嘛
this is what I'm talkin' about!
-"托德老爹"  -去他的托德吧
- "Toddfather"? - Oh, screw Todd!
现在史蒂夫才是她老爹
Steve's her daddy now.
你刚是用第三人称指代自己了吗
Did you just talk about yourself in the third person?
他刚刚是不是叫自己老爹了
Did he just call himself daddy?
好了  我们去哪
All right, where are we going?
-气象顶  -气象啥
- Weathertop. - Weather-what?
-快开吧  -知道了  老天
- Just drive. - Okay. Jesus!
托德老爹
第一层的钥匙
Bottom lock,
第二层的钥匙
second-to-top lock,
第三层的钥匙
third-to-top lock,
最高层的钥匙
top lock.
听我说  我得结束这一切
Listen to me, I need to end this,
但是我马上就回来  好吗
but I will be back before you know it, okay?
我不知道  妈
I don't know, Mom.
听着  你在那里会很安全
No, listen. You're gonna be safe there.
离这些都远远的
It's-- It's far away from all this.
你只要待在哥哥身边
You just stick close to your brother and--
他说什么就做什么
and do whatever he says.
不管怎么样  好吗
No matter what. Okay?
我担心的不是自己  妈  是你
I'm not worried about me, Mom, I'm worried about you.
宝贝  我会没事的
Oh, honey, I'm gonna be fine.
我会平安无事的
Okay? I'm gonna be fine.
好了
Okay, Mom.
知道了  妈  好了
Okay, Mom. That's enough.
-我一定会没事的  -我相信你
- I'm gonna be fine. - Okay.
妈  喘不上气了
Mom, I can't breathe.
-我精疲力尽了  但  -我要窒息了
- My battery's low, but... - You're suffocating me.
会恢复的
...it will recharge.
我知道它会  孩子
I know it will, kid.
我知道
I know.
我能战斗
I can fight.
比我们中的任何人都强
Better than any of us.
但是现在
But right now,
我只想让你安全
I need you safe.
这个东西要的是你
This thing is after you.
不是我
It's not after me.
你懂了吗
Do you understand?
我希望你能理解
I need you to understand.
好吗
Okay?
我们差不多该走了
We should probably go.
迈克
Mike?
注意安全
Be careful.
怎么了
What?
这是双人行动  双人
It's a two-man operation. Two!
-对  但计划有变  -计划有变
- Yeah, well, change of plans. - Change of plans?
能拜托你给他解释解释吗
Yeah. Will you explain it to him, please?
我们有两个选择  吉姆
We have two options here, Jim.
关掉那个机器  或者炸了它
We can turn the machine off, or we can explode it.
-是吗  谁说的  -造机器的人说的
- Oh, yeah, says who? - Says the man who built it!
我们想炸掉它
Yeah, and we wanna explode it!
不然我们这些英雄式的努力就白费了
Or else our heroic efforts will be for naught!
这是三人行动  吉姆  不是双人
This is a three-man operation, Jim, not two.
三人
Yeah, three.
一一  你在流血
El, you're bleeding.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
还可以
Yeah.
到了
Here. Okay.
过来
Here.
躺好
Lay down.
-有什么问题吗  -我不
- What's wrong? - I don't...
我不知道
I don't know.
别开玩笑了  快点
You can't be serious. Come on!
这车不是你妈刚买的吗
Didn't your mom just buy this car?
是啊  肯定没问题
Yes. I'm sure it's fine.
-你是不是忘关车灯了  -没有
- Did you leave the lights on? - No.
-车有油吗  -有
- Do we have gas? - Yes!
-加把劲吧  -住手  快住手
- Come on! - Whoa, whoa, whoa! Just stop, stop!
打开引擎盖
Pop the hood.
-什么情况  -怎么了
- What the hell? - What?
点火电缆不见了
The ignition cable's gone.
回商场里去
Back in the mall!
快回去
快快快  小心点
Go! Go, go, go! Be careful!
快走  快走
Go! Go!
快快快
Go, go, go!
所以我像扯杂草一样把电缆拽出来
So then I yank those cables like I'm pulling weeds.
警报会被触发
And that'll set off the alarm--
据阿列克西的说法是的  希望他安息
According to Alexei, may his soul rest in peace.
你们两个就有机会
Which should give you two an opening
去地下室里拿钥匙
to retrieve the keys from the vault.
然后我们跟着地图
And then we just follow the map
去到观察室  转动钥匙
to the observation room, turn the key--
砰  我们把这个鬼地方炸上天
Kaboom, we blow this sucker sky-high.
等裂缝关闭了
And then, once the rift is closed,
我们从通风管道逃回去
we escape back through the vents.
就在他们这些共产党的眼皮底下
Right under their commie noses.
然后回家
Then home free.
老天  就算这不是你的方案
Oh, God, just because it wasn't your plan doesn't mean
也不意味着就是一个坏方案
it was a bad plan.
我没说这是个坏方案
I didn't say it was a bad plan.
你发出了不满的哼唧
You made a noise.
-我才没有哼唧  -你也哼唧了
- I did not make a noise. - You did too.
我真心觉得这很不尊重人
I really think it's disrespectful...
你和哼唧声到底有什么过不去的
What is up with you and noises?
孩子们  孩子们
Children! Children!
这是个好方案
It is a good plan.
鉴于我们现在的情况和限制
A solid B, which is laudable,
这个方案坚实可靠  值得赞扬
given the situation and time constraints.
我敢说  如果一切顺利
Dare I say, if it all goes right...
他们甚至都不会知道我们来过
...they'll never even know we were here.
不许动
Stop right there!
别开枪  别开枪
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
文件  重要的文件
Documents, important documents--
要给中尉同志的
for the Lieutenant-Comrade!
他临时叫我们来
He called us, last minute.
原谅我们事发突然过来了
Pardon our sloppy appearance.
中尉  哪个中尉
Lieutenant? What Lieutenant?
中尉
Lieutenant...
莫洛托夫
Molotov?
我操
Oh, shit.
吉姆
Jim...
这太疯狂了
This is crazy.
天呐  吉姆  我  这...
Oh, my God. Jim, I... This...
我已经控制住局面了
I had it under control.
没错啊
Yeah, sure you did.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
临场发挥
I'm improvising.
天  这地方到底有多远  兄弟
Jesus, how far is this place, man?
放轻松  我们快到了
Relax, we're almost there.
苏茜一定很特别吧
Suzie must be pretty special, huh?
如果你造了这东西
I mean, if you built this thing
再大老远的把这东西拖到荒郊野岭
and lugged it all the way to the middle of nowhere
就为了跟她说话
just to talk to her?
没有真正完美的人
I mean, nobody's scientifically perfect,
但苏茜比任何人都
but Suzie's about as close to being perfect
无限趋近于完美
as any human could possibly be.
我觉得他是瞎编的
She sound made-up to me.
你觉得呢
She sound made-up to you?
-你干吗迟疑  史蒂夫  -我  我没有
- Why are you hesitating, Steve? -I'm-- I'm-- I'm not! I'm not!
我觉得挺真实的  绝对的  完全真实
I think she sounds real. You know, totally, absolutely real.
左  左转
Left. Turn left.
-左边根本没有路  -立马左转
- There's not a road here. - Turn left now!
我的天  抓紧了
Jesus! Hang on!
亨德森  你在搞什么
Henderson, where are we going?!
上啊
Up!
我的天呐  -我们上不去的
- Oh, Jesus! - We're not gonna make it!
上得去  加油  宝贝  加油啊
Yes, we are. Come on, baby. Come on, baby!
别这样
Come on!
不要  不要
Come on. Come on.
不要啊
Come on!
看来托德老爹也有能力不足的时候
Guess the Toddfather has its limitations.
冰淇淋小分队  收到请回答
Scoops Troop, do you copy?
冰淇淋小分队  我重复  收到请回答
Scoops Troop, I repeat, do you copy?
我们被困在商场里了
We're trapped in the mall
需要紧急转移
and in need of emergency transportation.
冰淇淋小分队  收到请回答  比利找到我们了
Scoops Troop, do you copy? Billy has found us.
他毁了我们的车  我们被困在商场里了
He has disabled our car and we are trapped in the mall.
重复一遍  比利把我们的车毁了
Repeat, Billy has disabled our car and...
你要杀了他  是不是
You're gonna kill him, aren't you?
这些都只是以防万一
This is just a precaution, okay?
不只是针对比利
And not just against Billy.
他能知道我们在这  那么吸灵魔也知道
If he knows we're here, so does the Mind Flayer.
冰淇淋小分队  我重复
Scoops Troop, I repeat,
我们需要紧急转移
we are in need of emergency transportation.
收到请回答
Do you copy?
冰淇淋小分队  收到请回答
Scoops Troop, do you copy?
那辆车应该不能开了吧
No chance that thing'll drive, right?
-史蒂夫  能听见吗  -我们不需要开它
- Steve, do you copy? - We don't need it to drive.
达斯汀
Dustin!
我们只需要它的点火电缆
We just need the ignition cable.
推啊
Push!
操
Shit!
让我试试
Let me try.
一一
El...
我可以的
I can do it.
有什么事吗
Can I help?
来拿东西
Picking up.
我认识你吗
Do I know you?
新来的
New arrivals.
昨天晚上刚到
Landed last night.
向阳光说再见吧
Say goodbye to sunlight.
当我们已有彼此
Who needs sunlight
谁还需要阳光  同志
when we have one another, comrade?
确实  同志
Indeed, comrade!
还有一瓶苏联红牌伏特加
And a bottle of Stolichnaya.
你干吗说这么多废话
Why are you talking so much?
他人还不错
He was nice.
-人还不错  -他是个不错的守卫
- He was nice? - He was a nice guard.
是啊  等着一切结束了
Yeah, I mean, we should probably invite him over
我们应该邀请他来玩
after all this is done.
是啊  我可以拿砂锅烤了他
Yeah, I can bake him a casserole.
拿点酒  分享一下快乐
Get a six-pack, share some laughs.
你懂的  喝一杯
You know, have a drink.
有人想交换任务吗
Anyone wanna trade jobs?
秃鹰小分队  收到请回答
Bald Eagle, do you copy?
秃鹰小分队  我重复
Bald Eagle, I repeat,
这里是冰淇淋小分队  收到请回答
this is Scoops Troop, do you copy?
收到
Yes, I copy.
呼号是
Call sign?
秃鹰小分队
Bald Eagle.
请重复
Please repeat.
-秃鹰  这里是秃鹰小分队  -收到
- Bald Eagle. This is Bald Eagle! - Copy that.
很高兴能听到你的声音
Good to hear your voice,
秃鹰小分队  你们到哪了
Bald Eagle. What's your 20?
我们已抵达通风口  有需要我会联系你们的
We reached the vent. I'll contact you when I need you.
在此之前  保持安静
Until then, silence.
收到  秃鹰小分队
Roger that, Bald Eagle.
这里是冰淇淋  即将沉默  好运  完毕
This is Scoops Troop, going radio silent. 10-10, over.
我讨厌小孩子
I hate children.
-记住  有人说话只需要  -点头微笑
- Remember, if anyone says anything, just  - Smile and nod.
好运
Good luck.
推
Push!
好的  太棒了
All right, great.
现在大家一起  准备好了吗
All right, now, all the way. Ready?
三二一  推
Three, two, one... Push!
跟你说了
Told you.
学好物理
Physics.
我们要怎么打开这个
How do we get it open?
应该有个门闩  检查一下方向盘底下
There should be a latch. Check under the wheel.
-看见没  -我不知道  等等
- You see it? - I don't know, hold on.
她在干什么
What's she doing?
一一
El.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
-你找到了吗  -我不知道
- Do you see it? - I don't know.
应该就在这里
It should be right here.
配电盘  配电盘
Distributor, distributor...
迈克
Mike.
找到了
Got it.
南茜
Nancy!
快走
Come on!
我们刚发现他们已经死了
We just found them like this.
美国人
The American.
时间太久了
It's taking too long.
-没事的  -不  有事  有事
- It's fine. - No, it's not. It is not.
她很可能会死
She could've died back there.
她差点就死了
She almost did.
现在她安全了  她在去莫里家的路上
Well, she's safe now. She's on her way to Murray's.
只有我们把它杀死
That thing won't find her,
那东西才不会找到她
not before we kill it.
不应该是这个样子的  好吗
This isn't the way this is supposed to work, all right?
你应该说  "对  我跟你说过的
You're supposed to say, "Yes, I told you so.
所以我们才需要回到孩子身边去"
That's why we needed to go back to the kids."
没错  然后你会说
Oh, yeah, and then you say something like...
"如果你把一切事情都说的
"Yeah, well, it's really hard to listen
好像世界末日要来临那样绝望
when you make everything sound like
真的会很难受"
it's the end of the goddamn world."
你知道
You know...
我想不管怎么样  即便有很多争吵
I think, despite everything, I mean, despite the arguing,
我还是觉得我们的合作很棒
I think we make a pretty good team.
我们都走到这里了  对不对
Well, we made it this far, didn't we?
没错
Yeah.
的确
We did.
所以
So, uh...
我到底能不能得到这份工作
did I get the job or what?
拜托
Ah, come on.
拜耶斯警探
Detective Byers.
有个戒指的  对吧
It has a ring, doesn't it?
警探  不住这里住还要管这里的事可有点难
It's kinda hard to serve in a town where you don't live, Detective.
你还是打算要搬走  你计划好了吧
You're still moving outta here. I mean, that is the plan, right?
我们看看后续情况如何吧
Eh, we'll see how it goes.
"后续情况如何"  什么情况
"How it goes"? How what goes?
你知道  如果我们可以能成功离开这里
You know, if-- if we actually do make it out of here,
我们值得庆祝一下  对吧
we-- we deserve to celebrate, right?
嗯
Yeah.
我是说
I mean...
是的
yes.
绝对需要
Absolutely.
听说恩佐餐厅很不错
I hear Enzo's is pretty good.
你觉得呢  周五八点钟如何
What do you say, Friday, eight o'clock?
一一周五喜欢看《迈阿密风云》
Uh, El likes to watch Miami Vice on Fridays.
十点开始  所以周五晚上我不能在外面待很晚
It... It starts at 10:00, so I-- I can't be out late on a Friday.
那就七点如何
Okay, how about 7:00, then?
七点
7:00?
恩佐餐厅  周五咱们那里见
Enzo's, Friday, I meet you there?
不行  你得去接我
No, you pick me up.
周五晚七点去接你
Picking you up 7:00 p.m. Friday.
嗯  那就约[约会]好了
Yeah, it's a date.
先澄清一下  因为我...如果...要是...
Just for clarification, just because I... I mean, just... If...
你说"约会"  所以我要说得清清楚楚
When you say "date," just so that we're crystal clear,
-这样不会有误会  怎么  -没错  霍普
- so there's no confusion-- Yeah? - Yeah, Hop?
别说了  不然我要改主意了
Stop talking or I'm gonna change my mind.
行  好的  行
Yeah, okay. Yeah.
行
Okay.
冰淇淋小分队  我是
Scoops Troop, this is...
秃鹰
Bald Eagle.
我到达了另一个交叉口
I've reached another junction.
-是什么  -第四交叉口
- This is what? - The fourth junction.
好吧  如果我没记错的话
All right, so if memory serves,
讲完小马宝莉论题后我们到了这里
this is right after the My Little Pony thesis.
-我们去了左边  所以他必须去右边  -右边
- We went left, so he has to go right. - Right.
向右飞  秃鹰
Fly right, Bald Eagle.
-向右飞  -收到  向右飞行
- Fly right. - Roger that, flying right.
小混蛋
Little shit.
小马宝莉论题是什么
What's the My Little Pony thesis?
别让他说这个
Don't get him started.
-让他说这个  告诉我  -各位
- Get him started? Just tell me-- - Hey, guys?
格里斯沃尔德一家  这里是冰淇淋小分队
Griswold Family, this is Scoops Troop!
收到吗  完毕
Do you copy? Over!
格里斯沃尔德一家  重复一遍
Griswold Family, I repeat,
这里是冰淇淋小分队  收到...
this is Scoops Troop. Do you--
格里斯沃尔德一家  收到吗
Griswold Family, do you copy?
收到吗
Do you copy?!
格里斯沃尔德一家  这里是冰淇淋小分队
Griswold Family, this is Scoops Troop.
请确认你方安全
Please confirm your safety!
你们在去秃鹰老巢的路上吗
Are you en route to Bald Eagle's nest?
请确认你方安全
Please confirm your safety!
有谁快点应答一下  有人在吗
Someone, please just answer. Is anyone there?
快回答
Just answer!
有人吗...
Anyone, please...
格里斯沃尔德一家  收到吗
Griswold Family, do you copy?
收到吗
Do you copy?!
-你们去哪里  -去帮他们逃离那里
- Where are you going?! - To get them the hell outta there!
待在这里  跟其他人保持联系
Stay here, contact the others!
-该死  -等等  罗宾
- Shit. - Wait, Robin!
保持联络
Stay in touch.
没问题
Got it.
秃鹰  这里是冰淇淋小分队  你们在哪里
Bald Eagle, this is Scoops Troop. What's your 20?
跟你说过了  没有回复
I told you, radio silence!
是的  但我们遇到一个问题
Yeah, but we have a problem.
什么样的问题
What kind of problem?
它转身了  如果我们现在上楼  就能成功
It's turned away. If we go up the stairs now, we'll make it.
-不可能  一一的腿这样  -我们得试试
- No way, not with El's leg. - We have to try.
还有另外一条
There's another way...
出去的路
to get out.
从GAP过去
Through the Gap.
好的
Okay.
就现在
Now.
秃鹰已经着陆
Bald Eagle has landed.
重复一遍
Repeat.
秃鹰已经着陆
Bald Eagle has landed.
好的
Okay.
拜托  还要多久
Come on, how much longer?
我不知道  我之前也没做过
I don't know, I've never done this before!
好吧
Okay.
好吧  行吧
Okay, okay!
准备好吧  小情侣们  你们要准备上场了
Get ready, lovebirds, you're almost up to bat.
该死
Oh, shit.
-你在干什么  -别担心
- What are you doing? - Don't worry.
快快快快快快快
Go! Go, go, go, go, go, go!
快走
Let's go.
米哈伊尔派你们来的吗
Did Mikhail send for you?
-好了  -好吧
- All right. - Okay.
把密码告诉我
Give me the code.
Six-six-two,
six-oh-eight,
oh-oh-four.
再来
again?
Six-six-two,
six-oh-eight,
oh-oh-four.
莫里
Murray?
你的密码
Your goddamn code...
不对
is wrong.
什么  你确定吗
What? Are you sure?
我确定
Yeah, I'm sure.
也可能是错的
Well, I-- I suppose it could be wrong.
怎么可能是错的
How could it be wrong?
密码是个著名的数字
The code is a number, a famous number.
普朗克常数  我以为我背住了
Planck's constant I-- I thought I knew it.
普朗克常数
Planck's constant.
-你知道吗  -记不住  你呢
- You know it? - Not by heart. You?
我不是书呆子  书呆子
I'm not a nerd, nerd.
他说是普朗克常数  我记得的
He told me it was Planck's constant, which I know.
我为什么要让他告诉我我已经知道的数
Why would I need him to give me a number I already know?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
跑跑跑
Go, go, go!
该死  启动汽车  快
Shit. Get the car started. Go!
不不不  拜托了
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no. Come on.
快  我们得走了
Come on. We gotta go!
快
Come on!
我们得走了
We gotta go!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
明天再问我
Ask me tomorrow?
该死
Oh, shit!
上车
Get in!
跑跑跑
Go, go, go, go! Go, go, go!
犹他州  盐湖城
苏茜  你收到吗
Suzie, do you copy?
我是苏茜  我收到了
This is Suzie. I copy.
-苏茜  -达斯宝贝
- Suzie! - Dusty-bun?
"达斯宝贝"
"Dusty-bun"?
你去哪了
Where have you been?
真抱歉  我太忙了
I'm so, so sorry. I-- I've been really busy...
我在努力从苏联人和怪物手中拯救世界
uh, trying to save the world from Russians and monsters.
当然了
Of course you have.
快问数字
Get the goddamn number already!
那是谁
Who was that?
是...
It was...
我不知道  好像是干扰
Uh, I don't know, actually. I think it was just some interference.
我们把频率改到
So, why don't we, uh, change frequency
14.158吧
to 14.158?
收到  换频道  等待
Copy that, shifting frequency. Standby.
-达斯宝贝  收到吗  -收到  苏茜宝
- Dusty-bun, you copy? - I copy, Suzie-poo.
现在清晰多了  谢谢
It sounds much better now, thanks.
-苏茜  -听着
- Suzie. - Okay, so, listen,
你知道普朗克常数吗
do you know Planck's constant?
你知道地球环绕太阳吗
Do you know the Earth orbits the sun?
好  我知道是6开头的  然后...
Okay, so I know it starts with two sixes, and then a...
是什么来着
W-What is it?
我想理清楚
Okay, let me just be clear on this.
我一周没你的消息了
I haven't heard from you in a week,
现在你想问一个你该知道的
and now you want a mathematical equation
数学等式  好去拯救世界吗
that you should know so you can... save the world?
苏茜宝  我保证
Suzie-poo, I promise,
我会尽快弥补你的
I will make it up to you as soon as possible.
你现在就弥补我吧
You can make it up to me now.
-什么  -我想听
- What? - I want to hear it.
-现在不行  -就现在  达斯宝贝
- Not right now. - Yes, now, Dusty-bun.
苏茜宝  这是急事
Suzie-poo, this is urgent.
是啊  你在拯救世界  我听到了
Yes, yes, you're saving the world, I heard you the first time,
但格德也在拯救地海
but Ged is also saving Earthsea
他就要面对影魔了
and he's about to confront the shadow,
所以苏茜通话结束
so this is Suzie, signing off.
等等  好吧
Wait, wait, wait! Okay.
好
Okay. Okay.
该死
Shit.
*转过身*
*Turn around*
*看你看到什么*
*Look at what you see*
*她的脸上*
*In her face*
*映射了你的梦*
*The mirror of your dreams*
*让我相信自己无所不在*
*Make believe I'm everywhere*
*沐浴在荣光之中*
*Given in the light*
*书页上写着*
*Written on the pages is*
*永不尽的*
*The answer to*
*故事的答案*
*A never-ending story*
*冲向星空*
*Reach the stars*
*为幻梦飞行*
*Fly a fantasy*
*梦我所梦*
*Dream a dream*
*你的设想会成为现实*
*And what you see will be*
*旋律将保守他们的秘密*
*Rhymes that keep their secrets will*
*在云彩后揭开*
*Unfold behind the clouds*
*在那彩虹之上*
*And there upon a rainbow is*
*永不尽的故事的答案*
*The answer to a never-ending story*
*故事*
*Story*
普朗克常数是6.62607004
Planck's constant is 6.62607004.
你刚拯救了世界
You just saved the world.
天呐  我好想你  达斯宝贝
Gosh, I miss you, Dusty-bun.
我更想你  苏茜宝
And I miss you more, Suzie-poo.
我更想你  乘以全银河系的星星
I miss you more, multiplied by all the stars in our galaxy.
-不  我想你...  -够了
- No, I miss you-- - Enough.
该死  跑跑跑
Shit! Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
它调头了
It's turning around.
-什么  -它调头了
- What? - It's turning around!
或许我们把它跑累了
Maybe we wore it out.
我觉得不是  坐稳
I don't think so. Hold on.
都出去
Everybody out.
Everybody out!
你准备好了结一切了吗
You ready to end this?
这里  进去
In here. In here.
好  快快快
Okay. Come on, come on, come on...
比利
Billy.
比利  你不用这样的
Billy, you don't have to do this.
比利  你叫比利  比利·哈格罗夫
Billy. Your name's Billy, Billy Hargrove.
你住在樱桃巷4819号  比利  求你
You live on 4819 Cherry Lane. Billy, please,
我是麦克斯  我是你...
I'm Max, I'm your--
莫里  你准备好了吗
Murray, you all set down there?
好了  但我这里来人了
All set, but I've got some company
我希望你能消灭他们
which I'd love you to obliterate.
没问题  等着
Will do. Hang tight.
数到三
On three.
好
一
One...
二
Two--
美国人
The Americans,
我找到他们了
I've found them--
别怕
Don't be afraid.
快结束了
It'll be over soon.
尽量  别动
Just try and stay... very still.
吸这个啊  你个混蛋
Flay this, you ugly piece of shit!
混蛋  过来
Hey, asshole! Over here!
-我们快没弹药了  -我知道
- We're almost out! - I know!
达斯汀  我们没时间了
Dustin! We're out of time!
快  快关上
Hurry! Close it now!
关上
Close it!
加油啊
Come on!
迈克
Mike...
Mike.
迈克
迈克  迈克  起来  你听得到吗  迈克
Mike. Mike. Mike, get up. Mike, can you hear me? Mike! Mike!
过来
Hey, come on.
你没事吧
You okay?
一一呢
Where's El?
别管我  住手
Leave me alone! Stop it!
-妈妈  -这是你的新妹妹
- Mom! - This is your new sister.
至少有两米高
...at least seven feet.
两米
Seven... feet.
你对她说
You told her...
浪有两米高
the wave was seven feet.
好啊
Yeah!
你在海滩上跑向她
You ran to her, on the beach.
还有海鸥
There were seagulls.
她戴了顶帽子
She wore a hat...
系着蓝色缎带
...with a blue ribbon.
长裙子
A long dress...
上面有红蓝色的花
with a blue and red flower.
黄拖鞋
Yell-- Yellow sandals,
上面都是沙子
covered in sand.
她很漂亮
She was pretty.
她真的很漂亮
She was really pretty.
你...
And you...
你很开心
you were happy.
地狱见
I'll see you in hell!
来吧
Hit me.
没了
We're out!
该死
Damn it!
不
No!
快关上
Close it now!
关上
Close it!
比利
Billy!
-一一  -迈克
- El. - Mike!
比利
Billy?
比利  比利  起来啊  比利  求你
Billy. Billy, Billy, get up, please. Billy, get up, please, please.
-对不起  -比利
- I'm sorry. - Billy...
比利  比利
Billy. Billy.
比利  醒醒  求你  比利
Billy, wake up. Billy, get up. Please, Billy...
比利
Billy!
Billy...
对不起
I'm sorry.
没事了
It's okay. It's okay.
霍普
Hop.
吉姆  吉姆呢
Jim. Where's Jim?
我们走  快
Let's go! Go! Come on!
你没事吧
You all right?
举起手来
Hands up!
别开枪  美国人  我们是美国人
Don't shoot! American! We're Americans! Americans!
我们走
Hey, come on, let's go!
快走
Go, go!
谢天谢地
Thank God!
三个月后
顶尖新闻
欢迎来到印第安纳州霍金斯
Welcome to Hawkins, Indiana,
这个好地方适合成长
a wonderful place to grow up,
抚养家庭
to raise your family,
遛狗
to walk your dog.
但是
But then...
国庆节那天  风云突变
...on July Fourth, everything changed.
一场重大惨剧降临小镇
A terrible tragedy struck this small town.
丑闻震惊小镇
三人死亡
但这不是小镇第一次遭遇惨剧了
But this was not this small town's first brush with tragedy.
英雄局长死于大火
镇民要求主持正义
睿侠月度员工
神秘死亡  政府掩盖
Mysterious deaths, government cover-ups,
政府腐败  据称掩盖事件后  小镇陷入悲痛
一场奇怪的化学品泄漏
a bizarre chemical leak.
化学品泄漏
都有关联吗
Is it all linked?
都是巨大的阴谋吗
All a vast conspiracy?
阴谋
是否全怪一位腐败倒台的镇长
The fault of a disgraced, corrupt mayor?
镇长被攻击
还是说中心地带发生了更大的事
Or is something more going on in the heartland?
欢迎来到霍金斯地狱
这个小镇会是被诅咒了吗
Some believe a rise in Satanism is to blame.
龙与地下城
地下城法师指导
想知道真相
To find out,
今晚8点请收看《中心地带恐怖事件》
tune in tonight at 8:00 p.m. for "Horror in the Heartland"
尽在顶尖新闻
on Cutting Edge.
家庭音像
你拿你妈当推荐人
You put your mom down as a reference?
是啊  怎么不行  她非常受尊敬的
Yeah. Why not? She's, like, super well-respected.
你真是个呆瓜
You're such a dingus.
什么...
Wha--
说清楚  我们不是被解雇的
Uh, just to be clear, we weren't fired, you know.
商场烧毁了  还死了好几个人
The mall burned down and, like, killed a bunch of people.
多谢告知  我不知道呢
Thanks for sharing. Didn't know.
三部最喜欢电影  说
Three favorite movies. Go.
《桃色公寓》
The Apartment,
《隐秘堡垒》《天堂的孩子》
Hidden Fortress, Children of Paradise.
你  说
You, go.
-最爱电影吗  -我口吃了吗
- Favorite movies? - Did I stutter?
《动物屋》绝对的
Animal House, for sure.
看着我  哈灵顿
Eyes on me, Harrington.
嗯
Yeah.
《星战》
Star Wars.
《新希望》吗
A New Hope?
什么
A new what-now?
哪部《星战》
Which Star Wars?
有泰迪熊的那个呗
The one with the teddy bears.
没有吗  刚出来那部
No? Uh... Oh, the one that just came out.
刚出来的那部电影
The movie that just came out.
就是有德洛雷安和艾利克斯·基顿的那部
The one with the DeLorean and Alex P. Keaton,
他想上他老妈
and he's trying to bang his mom.
时间
The time...
那是我最喜欢的三部  经典
Yeah, those are my top three. Classics.
你星期一来
You start Monday.
你永远别来
You start never.
可以  给我们点时间吗
Will you just, um... Will you give us a minute?
为什么
Why?
史蒂夫
Steve.
好吧  你得明白  基斯
All right, you have to understand, Keith,
我知道他的品位比较俗
I know his taste is a bit pedestrian,
但呆瓜有其他优点
but the dingus has other qualities.
他就是最高级别的蠢蛋  罗宾
He's a douchebag of the highest order, Robin.
他在高中时的确对我们很差
He was a bit of a prick to us in high school,
我承认
I'll grant you that,
但他现在仍是
but he remains...
女生磁铁
a total chick magnet.
是啊  那跟我有什么关系
Yeah, okay, and this is relevant to me how?
地球呼叫基斯
Uh, Earth to Keith.
女士们会专为见他而走进来
The ladies will come in just to see him.
她们会成群地来
They'll come in in droves.
成群  基斯
Droves, Keith.
我们当初冰淇淋卖得太火
We sold so much ice cream,
他们不得不从密歇根二次进货
they had to get a second shipment in from Michigan.
密歇根州啊  基斯
Goddamn Michigan, Keith.
那些女人
And these ladies...
那些女人都很性感
These ladies are hot.
她们可性感了
They're so very hot.
史蒂夫一个人应付不来
And there are too many of them for little Steve.
他需要协助
He needs assistance.
他需要你的协助  基斯
He needs your assistance, Keith.
你有什么好处  你喜欢他吗
What's in it for you? You got a thing for him or something?
该死  这...
Goddammit. This is--
我们只是...
We're just, um...
我们只是朋友
We're just friends.
《开放的美国学府》  听说过吗
Fast Times. Fast Times. Ever heard of it?
我的最爱三部之一  基斯
Top three for me, Keith.
-慢点  -抱歉
- Slow down. - Sorry. Sorry.
-还行吗  -嗯
- Still got it? - Yeah, yeah.
搬家公司
*转过身*
*Turn around*
待售
*看你看到什么*
*Look at what you see*
*她的脸上*
*In her face*
*映射了你的梦*
*The mirror of your dreams*
*旋律将保守他们的秘密*
*Rhymes that keep their secrets*
*在云彩后揭开*
*Will unfold behind the clouds*
等等  我们唱得对吗
Wait, did we get that verse right?
是"在云彩后揭开"吗
It's "unfold behind the clouds"?
对  但你们都唱毁了  能不能停下
Yeah, but you're butchering it, so could you please stop?
那就一起唱  达斯宝贝
So then join in, Dusty-bun.
是啊  达斯宝贝  一起唱嘛
Yeah, come on, Dusty-bun, why don't you join us?
你们真好笑  该去上《卡森秀》
You guys are so funny, you should be on Carson.
-不能听你唱一遍吗  -不能
- Can't we just hear your rendition? - No.
求你  就一段
Please? Just one verse?
不要  那是只唱给苏茜听的
No. No way. It's reserved for Suzie's ears and Suzie's ears alone.
*转过身*
*Turn around*
*看你看到什么*
*Look at what you see*
*她的脸上*
*In their face*
*映射了你的梦*
*The mirror of your dreams*
你们闭嘴啦
Shut up, you guys.
*旋律将保守他们的秘密*
*Rhymes that keep their secrets*
闭嘴  你们闭嘴吧
Stop! You guys, please, shut up.
龙与地下城
哥们  那是捐赠箱
Whoa, dude. That's the donation box.
我知道  等我回来用你的好了
I know. I'll just use yours when I come back.
如果我们还玩的话
I mean, if we still wanna play.
好啊  如果你想跟别人一起玩呢
Yeah, but what if you want to join another party?
不会的
Not possible.
都...
Is that...
搬走了吗
everything?
看来是的
I guess so.
17年人生
Seventeen years of my life...
一天就打包好了
packed up in one day.
如果我
What if I just...
不让你走呢
don't let you go?
我想
I think...
新屋主会赶走我们的
the new owners might kick us out.
你可以住我们家地下室
You could stay in our basement.
你爸爸会喜欢的
Your dad'd love that.
我们可以把你藏在帐篷里
We could hide you in a tent,
就像一一
like El.
没事的
It's gonna be okay.
就像一位智者曾说
As a wise man once said...
我们共同经历过创伤
we've got shared trauma.
再经历点又何妨
So what's a little more, right?
What's a little more?
会恢复的
They'll come back.
我知道
I know they will.
谢谢
Thanks.
-你带对讲机了吧  -嗯
- You packed your walkie, right? - Yes.
因为我会偷走达斯汀的脑波机
Because you know that I'm gonna steal Cerebro from Dustin
一个劲地呼叫你  你只能烦得关掉它
and call you so much, you're gonna have to turn it off, right?
你跟你妈妈谈了吗
Did you talk to your mom?
感恩节的事
About Thanksgiving?
当然  她批准了  我会去的
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah. I got the okay. I'll be there.
我还想
And then I was thinking
或许你圣诞节可以来这里过
maybe you could come up here for Christmas.
威尔也是
And Will, too.
你可以在圣诞节前后来
You can come before or after Christmas,
看拜耶斯太太的意思
or whatever Mrs. Byers wants,
但我觉得圣诞节那天会很好玩
but I was thinking Christmas Day could be super fun,
因为我们那时都有棒棒的新礼物可玩
because we'd all have cool new presents to play with and, uh...
抱歉  我听上去像个7岁小孩
Sorry, that made me sound like a seven-year-old.
我也喜欢礼物
I like presents, too.
嗯  好啊
Yeah, cool. Yeah.
我也喜欢礼物
I like-- I like presents, too.
好啊
Cool.
迈克
Mike?
怎么
Yeah?
记得那天
Remember that day...
在小屋  你对麦克斯说的话
at the cabin, you were talking to Max?
我不太懂
I don't think I follow.
你说到了你的感情
You talked about your-- your feelings,
你的心
your heart.
是啊  那个啊  好久之前了
Oh, yeah, that. Man, that was so long ago.
那就是一时冲口而出
That was really heat of the moment stuff,
我们当时在吵架
and we were arguing and...
我不记得
I don't really remember...
我说了什么
What did I say, exactly?
迈克
Mike...
我也爱你
I love you, too.
霍普
捐赠箱
Donation box?
好的
Uh, yeah, sure.
那是什么
What is that?
霍普为你和迈克写的讲稿
It-- It's the speech Hop wrote for you and Mike.
讲稿
Speech?
是啊  你们的谈心
Yeah. You know, the heart-to-heart.
他没跟你们谈  是吧
He never talked to you, did he?
我能读读吗
Can I read?
"有件事我早想跟你们谈谈了
"There's something I've been wanting to talk to you both about.
我知道谈这个很困难
I know this is a difficult conversation,
但我非常在乎你们俩
but I care about you both very much.
我也知道你们很在乎彼此
And I know that you care about each other very much.
所以我们一定要
And that's why it's important
立下这些规矩  以便今后
that we set these boundaries moving forward,
建立一个良好环境
so we can build an environment...
让我们都能感到
where we all feel...
自在
comfortable...
被信任
trusted...
开放
and open...
可以分享我们的情绪"
to sharing our feelings."
情绪
Feelings.
天呐
Jesus.
事实上
The truth is,
很久以来  我都忘记那是什么了
for so long, I'd forgotten what those even were.
我一直困在一个地方
I've been stuck in one place,
可以说困在一个洞里
in a cave, you might say.
深深的黑暗的洞
A deep, dark cave.
然后  我在林子里留了些松饼
And then, I left some Eggos out in the woods,
你就走进了我的生活
and you came into my life and...
很久以来  头一次
for the first time in a long time,
我开始有感觉了
I started to feel things again.
我开始感觉快乐了
I started to feel happy.
但近来  我想我觉得...
But, lately, I guess I've been feeling...
与你疏离了
distant from you.
就好像你
Like you're...
你在远离我
you're pulling away from me or something.
我想念每晚跟你玩棋盘游戏
I miss playing board games every night,
日出时做三层冰冻松饼大餐
making triple-decker Eggo extravaganzas at sunrise,
睡觉之前  一起看电视
watching westerns together before we doze off.
但我知道你在长大
But I know you're getting older.
成长
Growing.
改变
Changing.
我猜
And I guess...
老实说
if I'm being really honest,
这才是让我害怕的
that's what scares me.
我不希望事情改变
I don't want things to change.
或许  这才是我来这里的原因
So, I think maybe that's why I came in here,
想停止那种改变
to try to maybe... stop that change.
逆转时间
To turn back the clock.
让一切回到从前
To make things go back to how they were.
离开霍金斯  早日归来
但我知道那是天真
But I know that's naive.
那不是
It's just...
人生的规律
not how life works.
人生不断向前
It's moving.
不管你喜不喜欢
Always moving, whether you like it or not.
有时是痛苦的
And, yeah, sometimes it's painful.
有时是悲伤的
Sometimes it's sad.
艾瑞卡
有时
And sometimes...
捐赠
是令人意外的
it's surprising.
快乐的
Happy.
所以知道吗
So, you know what?
龙与地下城
继续长大吧  孩子
Keep on growing up, kid.
别让我拦着你
Don't let me stop you.
犯错  然后吸取教训
Make mistakes, learn from 'em,
如果生活伤害了你  因为那是肯定会的
and when life hurts you, because it will,
记住那种痛苦
remember the hurt.
那是好事
The hurt is good.
那意味着你走出了洞
It means you're out of that cave.
但求你
But, please,
如果你不介意
if you don't mind,
为了你可怜的老爸
for the sake of your poor old dad,
门至少留三英寸
keep the door open three inches.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
嗯
Yeah.
该走了
Time to go?
嗯
Yeah.
我就出去
I'll be out in a minute.
好
Okay.
后面还有
苏联  堪察加半岛
不  不是那美国人
No. Not the American.
不  我求你  不要
No, I'm begging you... No! Don't!
不要  求你
No! Please! No! Don't!
别
No, don't!
别这样
Don't do this!
放开我
Let me go!
别丢下我
Don't leave me in here.
放我出去
Let me out,
我是无辜的
I'm innocent.
I'm innocent!
求你  求你
I'm begging you, please!